<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Card Games</string>

    <!--String constants for descriptions-->
    <string name="capitalism_description">
        Get rid of all your cards as quickly
        as possible to climb the capitalistic hierarchy.</string>
    <string name="mao_description">
        Get creative with the rules as you punish yourself
        for forgetting your own.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_description">
        Avoid getting points while coming up with an evil
        plan to give them to your friends(enemies).
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_description">
        Bet on how many trick you think you will take, but
        your friends will try to make sure you don\'t make your bet.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_description">
        Turn your entire hand into melds and hope that no
        one else has the cards that you need so badly.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for button text-->
    <string name="capitalism">Capitalism</string>
    <string name="mao">Mao</string>
    <string name="hearts">Hearts</string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge">Scotch Bridge</string>
    <string name="rummy">Rummy</string>

    <!---String constants for the short summaries-->
    <string name="capitalism_short_summary">
        Capitalism is a shedding game. The game employs a hierarchy that gives those
        at the top an advantage at the beginning of each round. This may sound
        unfair, but it makes it more rewarding when you overthrow those at the top.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_short_summary">
        Mao is a shedding game very similar to Uno. Mao lets the winner of each round
        to create a new secret rule. The rules are cumulative, meaning the game will
        become more difficult yet more fun.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_short_summary">
        Hearts is under the family of trick-taking games. What makes hearts interesting
        is that you are trying to avoid getting points. The game can also involve
        intense strategies as when you play which card is very important.
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_short_summary">
        Scotch Bridge is a trick-taking game that uses a trump suit. It tests your
        ability to evaluate your hand since you are to bet how many trick you
        think you are going to take during the round. It often involves a change
        in plan when you win or lose a trick unexpectedly.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_short_summary">
        Rummy falls under the family of card games also known as rummy. The objective
        of rummy card games is to form melds, or certain combinations of cards.
        Because of the nature of the game, both luck and skill are important in
        determining the winner.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the setup-->
    <string name="capitalism_setup">
        Players: 3+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: ~2 minutes per round
    </string>
    <string name="mao_setup">
        Players: 2+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 2-15 minutes per round
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_setup">
        Players: 4 is preferred (3 or 5 is also possible)
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 2-5 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_setup">
        Players: 4 is preferred (3 or 5 is also possible)
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 1-5 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_setup">
        Players: 2+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 1-10 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the rules-->
    <string name="capitalism_rules">
        First round: All of the cards are dealt out as evenly as possible to all of
        the players. The 3 of clubs starts the play. The person who has the
        3 of clubs can start the pile with as many 3\'s as they wish.
        \n\nRanking order: The cards are ranked, from lowest to highest: 3, 4, 5, 6,
        7, 8, 9, 10, J, Q, K, A. 2\'s are special cards and are not part of the ranking.
        \n\nPlay: The person who starts a pile determines how many cards can be played
        at once until the pile is cleared. A player can start a pile with 1, 2, or
        3 cards of the same rank. The play continues clockwise. The next player can
        either choose to play or pass. If they choose to play, they must play the same
        number of cards as the person who started the pile. The rank of the cards played
        must be the same as or higher than that of the cards previously on top of the pile.
        A player can choose to pass even if they can play. If every player passes, then
        the pile clears and the player who played the last card can start a new pile.
        \n\nSkips: If the previous player plays a single card and you play a card
        of the same rank, the next player is skipped and play continues with the player
        after them.
        \n\n2\'s: When you play a 2 on your turn, the pile clears and you can start a
        new pile. You are not allowed to start a pile with a 2. Also, having a 2 as your
        last card automatically demotes you to last place.
        \n\nCompletions: Completions can be played out of turn. You can make a completion
        when you can place cards on top of the pile and make 4 cards of the same rank.
        However, you must do this before someone else plays more cards on top of the pile.
        You can even make a completion when you are skipped. After a completion, the pile
        clears and you start the next pile.
        \n\nEnding a round: The first person to get rid of all of their cards becomes
        \"president\". The round continues until all of the players have gotten rid of all
        of their cards. If a player who has gotten rid of all of their cards happens to have
        another turn, then it is the turn of the player who is sitting clockwise to them.
        The second person to finish becomes \"vice president\". The second to last person to
        finish becomes \"vice scum\" and the player who came in last is \"scum\". The titles
        given to the players can be changed to whatever the players want as long as there is
        a hierarchy.
        \n\nStarting a new round: The dealer deals out as many piles as there are players
        as evenly as possible. The top card of each pile is flipped over. If the top cards
        of any two piles are the same rank, then the next card of those piles are also flipped
        over until all of the top cards are unique in rank. The \"president\" from the
        previous round gets to pick first which pile they want as their hand. The order
        that the players pick their hands is the same as the order they finished in the
        previous round. Now the president and vice president gets to ask for cards from the
        vice scum and scum, respectively. The president asks the scum if they have a card of
        a certain rank, or a 2. The scum cannot lie. They must give the card that the president
        asks for to the president. The president asks for 2 cards from the scum and gives
        back 2 cards of the president\'s choice. The vice president does the same with the
        vice scum but they only exchange 1 card.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_rules">
        Each player is dealt 7 cards (or fewer if there are many people). The remaining cards
        are placed in the center facedown and one card is flipped over. The first player must play
        a card of the same suit or of the same rank as that card. The next player must do the
        same with the new top card and play continues clockwise like that. If a player cannot
        play, they must draw a card from the top of the facedown pile. If there are no more cards
        left in the facedown pile, the faceup pile in reshuffled except for the top card, which
        remains the top card after the shuffle.
        \n\nMao: A player who has only one card left must announce \"Mao\" or else they would be
        penalized with 2 cards from the facedown pile.
        \n\nEnding the round: A player wins the round if they end their turn with no cards left.
        \n\nAdditional rules: The player who won the previous round gets to choose a new rule
        to be added into the game. The rules require a player to do a certain action (or not
        do a certain action) when something happens. The rules cannot target a specific player
        or be a new winning condition. If someone breaks a rule, they are penalized 1 card from
        the facedown pile and they are told what they did or did not do, but not when the rule is
        triggered.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_rules">
        Each player is dealt 13 cards.
        \n\nPassing: At the beginning of each round, 3 cards are passed to another player based
        on which round it is. The passing order repeats every 4 rounds: pass left, pass right,
        pass across, no pass.
        \n\nPlay: Each round consists of 13 tricks. The player with the 2 of clubs starts the
        first trick and for other tricks, the winner of each tricks starts the next. Play
        continues clockwise. Players
        must play a card of the same suit as the card that started the trick. If they do not
        have that suit, then they can play anything they wish. A player wins the trick by
        playing the highest ranked card of the suit that started the trick, with aces being
        the highest ranked.
        \n\nBreaking Hearts: A player has only lead a trick with hearts if hearts have been
        \"broken\" or have only hearts left in their hand. To \"break\" hearts, you have to
        legally play a heart card in a trick.
        \n\nScoring: Players get points based on the points of the cards in the tricks they have
        won. Each heart card is worth 1 point. The queen of spades is worth 13 points.
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_rules">
        Rounds start with 1 card per player. The number of cards increase by 1 per round up to 13.
        Then it decreases by 1 down to 1. The position of dealer also changes to the person
        clockwise of the current dealer each round.
        \n\nBetting: Starting with the player to the left of the dealer and going clockwise,
        each player announces how many tricks they think they will take that round. The sum of
        the number of tricks each player bets cannot equal the number of cards each player has.
        Since the dealer bets last, they must bet a number of tricks so that this rules is not
        violated. This rule ensures that someone will not get exactly the number of tricks that
        they bet.
        \n\nPlay: Each round consists of tricks. The player left of the dealer starts the
        first trick and for other tricks, the winner of each tricks starts the next. Play
        continues clockwise. Players
        must play a card of the same suit as the card that started the trick. If they do not
        have that suit, then they can play anything they wish. A player wins the trick by
        playing the highest ranked card of the suit that started the trick, with aces being
        the highest ranked, or if there is a trump card, the highest ranked card of the trump suit.
        The dealer flips over 1 card from the remaining facedown cards. The suit of the card
        is trump suit. In the round with 13 cards per player, there is not a trump suit.
        \n\nScoring: If a player wins exactly the number of tricks that they bet, they get 10 times
        that number in points. If a player fails to make their bet exactly, they lose 10 times
        the number of tricks they were over or under the bet they made, in points.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_rules">
        Each player is dealt 7 cards. The remaining cards are placed in the center in a facedown
        pile. One card is flipped over to start the faceup pile.
        \n\nPlay: Players can either take the top card from the facedown pile or faceup pile.
        Players can then meld (or put down in front of them) a run or a set. A player can
        only meld once per turn. A player can also \"lay off\" a card by adding to melds that
        are already on the table. A player ends their turn by discarding a card onto the faceup
        pile.
        \n\nRun: A run is a sequence of at least 3 cards in order of the same suit. Aces are low
        only in this game. A23 of hearts in a valid run but QKA of hearts is not.
        \n\nSet: A set is 3 or 4 cards of the same rank.
        \n\nEnding a round: A round ends when one player has no more cards in their hand. The
        get the points on the cards that other players are still holding (i.e. not yet melded
        or laid off). Aces are worth 1 point. 2\'s through 10\'s are worth the same number of
        points as the number on the card. Jacks, queens, and kings are all worth 10 points each.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the endgame-->
    <string name="capitalism_endgame">
        There is no official end to the game (like capitalism in the real world), but
        you can use metrics such as number of presidencies to determine the winner.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_endgame">
        There is no official end to the game, but it usually ends when there are too many
        rules and players are penalized too often.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_endgame">
        The game ends when a player reaches 100 points. The player with the fewest number of
        points wins the game
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_endgame">
        The player with the most points after all of the rounds wins.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_endgame">
        The first to reach an agreed upon number of point wins. Alternatively, the player
        with the most points after an agreed upon number of rounds wins.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the variations-->
    <string name="capitalism_variations">
        Reverses: Jokers can be added to the deck and be used to reverse the direction of play
        \n\nCommunism: The person who finished last in the previous round can ask for 2 cards
        from the person who finished first. Likewise, the person who was second to last can
        ask for 1 card from the person who finished second.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_variations">
        Players can start the game with an agreed upon set of rules to encourage more action.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_variations">
        Points can be assigned to other cards. Common cards are the jack of diamonds, worth
        -10 points, and the 7 of clubs, worth 7 points.
        \n\n Trick extension: If an 8 (or some other rank) is played in trick, the player
        who would have won the trick does not take cards. Instead, another trick is played
        and the winner of the second trick takes all of the cards in the middle. It is possible
        to play another 8 in the second trick, extending the trick to another trick.
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_variations">
        The full game can take a long time. Players can elect to play half of the full game,
        stopping at the round with 13 cards per players.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_variations">
        There is a whole family of card games related to this basic version of rummy. Common
        rummy games include Rummy 500, Gin Rummy, and Canasta.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for headers-->
    <string name="setup">Setup:</string>
    <string name="rules">Rules:</string>
    <string name="endgame">Endgame:</string>
    <string name="variations">Variations:</string>

    <!--String constants for email-->
    <string name="suggestions">Suggestions?</string>
    <string name="email">baliu@vassar.edu</string>
    <string name="email_subject">Suggestions for Card Game app</string>
</resources>
