<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Card Games</string>

    <!--String constants for descriptions-->
    <string name="capitalism_description">
        Get rid of all your cards as quickly
        as possible to climb the capitalistic hierarchy.</string>
    <string name="mao_description">
        Get creative with the rules as you punish yourself
        for forgetting your own.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_description">
        Avoid getting points while coming up with an evil
        plan to give them to your friends(enemies).
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_description">
        Bet on how many trick you think you will take, but
        your friends will try to make sure you don\'t make your bet.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_description">
        Turn your entire hand into melds and hope that no
        one else has the cards that you need so badly.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for button text-->
    <string name="capitalism">Capitalism</string>
    <string name="mao">Mao</string>
    <string name="hearts">Hearts</string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge">Scotch Bridge</string>
    <string name="rummy">Rummy</string>

    <!---String constants for the short summaries-->
    <string name="capitalism_short_summary">
        Capitalism is a shedding game. The game employs a hierarchy that gives those
        at the top an advantage at the beginning of each round. This may sound
        unfair, but it makes it more rewarding when you overthrow those at the top.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_short_summary">
        Mao is a shedding game very similar to Uno. Mao lets the winner of each round
        to create a new secret rule. The rules are cumulative, meaning the game will
        become more difficult yet more fun.
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_short_summary">
        Hearts is under the family of trick-taking games. What makes hearts interesting
        is that you are trying to avoid getting points. The game can also involve
        intense strategies as when you play which card is very important.
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_short_summary">
        Scotch Bridge is a trick-taking game that uses a trump suit. It tests your
        ability to evaluate your hand since you are to bet how many trick you
        think you are going to take during the round. It often involves a change
        in plan when you win or lose a trick unexpectedly.
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_short_summary">
        Rummy falls under the family of card games also known as rummy. The objective
        of rummy card games is to form melds, or certain combinations of cards.
        Because of the nature of the game, both luck and skill are important in
        determining the winner.
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the setup-->
    <string name="capitalism_setup">
        Players: 3+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: ~2 minutes per round
    </string>
    <string name="mao_setup">
        Players: 2+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 2-15 minutes per round
    </string>
    <string name="hearts_setup">
        Players: 4 is preferred (3 or 5 is also possible)
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 2-5 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_setup">
        Players: 4 is preferred (3 or 5 is also possible)
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 1-5 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>
    <string name="rummy_setup">
        Players: 2+
        \nDeck: Standard 52-card deck
        \nPlaying Time: 1-10 minutes per round, 1-2 hours per game
    </string>

    <!--String constants for the rules-->
    <string name="capitalism_rules">
        First round: All of the cards are dealt out as evenly as possible to all of
        the players. The 3 of clubs starts the play. The person who has the
        3 of clubs can start the pile with as many 3\'s as they wish.
        \n\nPlay: The person who starts a pile determines how many cards can be played
        at once until the pile is cleared.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_rules"></string>
    <string name="hearts_rules"></string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_rules"></string>
    <string name="rummy_rules"></string>

    <!--String constants for the endgame-->
    <string name="capitalism_endgame">
        There is no official end to the game (like capitalism in the real world), but
        you can use metrics such as number of presidencies to determine the winner.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_endgame"></string>
    <string name="hearts_endgame"></string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_endgame"></string>
    <string name="rummy_endgame"></string>

    <!--String constants for the variations-->
    <string name="capitalism_variations">
        Reverses: Jokers can be added to the deck and be used to reverse the direction of play
        \n\nCommunism: The person who finished last in the previous round can ask for 2 cards
        from the person who finished first. Likewise, the person who was second to last can
        ask for 1 card from the person who finished second.
    </string>
    <string name="mao_variations"></string>
    <string name="hearts_variations"></string>
    <string name="scotch_bridge_variations"></string>
    <string name="rummy_variations"></string>

    <!--String constants for headers-->
    <string name="setup">Setup:</string>
    <string name="rules">Rules:</string>
    <string name="endgame">Endgame:</string>
    <string name="variations">Variations:</string>
</resources>
